就像我们的应用程序现在一样
as our app stands now
当我们收到斜线熊的请求时
when we get a request for slash bears
我们用这个简单的字符串响应
we respond with this simple string
但这是一个网络服务器
but this being a web server in all
我们真的应该用一些 html 来回应
we really should respond with some html
是的，我们会这样做
yeah and we'll do that
通过使用
by using
e中的一些转换函数
some of the transformation functions that are in the e
新模块
new module
但让我们从组织我们的代码开始
but let's start off by organizing our code to look
更像是一个遵循 nvc 模式的 web 框架
more like a web framework that follows the nvc pattern
例如 Phoenix 或 rails
such as Phoenix or rails
通常在 Web 框架中
typically in a web framework
路线将简单地调度或
the routes would simply dispatch or
委托给控制器
delegate to a controller
是的，我们可以做到
yeah we can do that
我们将在这里定义一个新的控制器
we'll define a new controller over here
新文件，我们将其称为裸控制器
new file and we're going to call it bare controller
我们将设置模块
we'll set up the module
这将是调查裸控制器
it's going to be survey bare controller
把它存起来
save that away
然后我们将使用它
and then we're going to use that back
在我们的处理程序模块中
over in our handler module
所以在处理程序的顶部，我将把它命名为
so at the top of a handler I'm going to alias that in
然后我们想在
and then we want to use that in the
熊路线就在这里
bears route right here
所以我要把这条线删掉
so I'm just going to cut this line out
相反，我们将调用熊控制器
and instead we'll call bear controller
我们假设我们会有一个
and we'll assume we're going to have a
称为索引的函数
function called index
然后我们将传入那个 co 和 v 地图
and then we're going to pass in that co and v map
那样
that way
该函数可以更新它并返回一个新副本
the function can update it and return a new copy
所以然后回来
so then back
在我们的裸控制器中，我们只需要找到索引
over in our bare controller we just need to find index
它需要 co 和 v
it takes co and v
我要粘贴我从
and I'm going to paste in what I cut out from the
其他文件我们想做类似的事情
other file we want to do a similar thing
对于裸斜线一条路线
for the bare slash one route
我们想把它委托给一个显示功能
we want to delegate it to a show function
是的，所以我会把它从这里剪掉
yeah so I'll cut this out of here
这将是裸控制器
this is going to be bare controller
点显示
dot show
我们会通过它的婊子
we'll pass it cunt
它也需要那个 id
and it's also going to need that id
所以我们将它作为第二个参数传递
so we'll pass it as the second parameter
然后在控制器中
then over in the controller
我们会安排表演
we'll set up show
在 id 中看到一个 v，我将其粘贴到
see one v in the id and I'll paste that in
所以这会起作用
so this will work
但还有另一种方法可以做到
but there's another way to do it
而不是像这样传递一个id
as opposed to passing in an id like this
如果我们想打包那个 id 怎么办
what if we wanted to package up that id
与其他参数，因为 id 真的只是
with the other parameters because id's really just a
请求参数
request parameter
所以我们要做的是合并它
so what we want to do is merge it
进入现有参数
into the existing parameters
你会记得那些在 co 和 v paras
and you'll remember that those are in co and v paras
所以让我们这样做
so let's do it this way
参数等于地图放
param's equals map put
我们将采用 co 和 v paras 并添加它
we'll take co and v paras and we'll add to it
一个名为 id 的键
a key called id
和 id 值
and the id value
然后我们会转身把它作为第二个传递
and then we'll turn around and pass that as the second
我们的 show 函数的参数
parameter to our show function
如果我们在节目中这样做
and if we do that back over here in show
然后不是拿 id 这将是一张地图
then instead of taking id this is going to be a map
我们可以对其进行模式匹配
and we can just pattern match on it
所以我们想像这样提取 id 的值
so we want to extract the value of the id like that
然后我们在这里引用 id
and then we reference id right here
所以这也可以
so this will work just as well
只是给了我们更多的灵活性
just gives us a little bit more flexibility
我们可以拿整个婴儿车地图
we can take the entire prams map
然后做一些模式匹配
and then do some pattern matching
弄清楚里面有什么
figure out what's inside of there
你可以想象可能有
you can imagine that there might be
其他参数正在进一步设置管道
other parameters being set further up the pipeline
所以这只是为动作提供了所有参数
so this just gives the action all the parameters
它可以弄清楚如何处理这些
and it can figure out what to do with those
所以我们还有一个要走
so we have one more to go
对于我们要委托给创建的发布路线
for the post route we want to delegate to a create
功能
function
这将是裸控制器
this would be bare controller
创建
create
通过它 co 和 v
pass it co and v
它需要发布的参数
and it's going to need the posted parameters
所以我们要通过
so we're going to pass
co 和 v 段
co and v paras
记住那些张贴的参数
remember those posted parameters
被解析出来，我们把它们放在 co 和 v 参数中
get parsed out and we put them in co and v params
我们在课程的早些时候做了一点
which we did a bit earlier in the course
然后在控制器中
then over in the controller
我们将定义创建
we'll define create
带上ceo和v，还带上paras
take ceo and v and also takes paras
我会把它粘贴进去
and I'll just paste that in
现在因为这里的参数名称是 para
now because the name of the argument here is para
我们不必参考封面段落
we don't have to reference cover paras
它只是 param 的类型
it's just going to be param's type
然后在这里
and then over here
我们有熊的名字
we've got the name of the bear
它只是参数
it's just going to be params
现在更进一步
now to take this one step further
我们知道我们可以对此进行模式匹配
we know that we can pattern match on this
所以我们可以这样做
so we could do it this way
提取名称
extract the name
提取类型
extract the type
如果我们想
and if we wanted to
我们可以将其设置为
we could set this equal to
如果我们想要访问它
para if we wanted access to that
但是现在在这里我们有绑定到的类型
but now down here we have type that's bound to the
部分类型和
type that was in parts and
我们有名字
we have the name
我们把它存起来
we save that away
如果我们重新编译所有内容，则返回 ix
and back over an ix if we recompile everything
好吧，看起来一切仍然有效
well it looks like everything still worked
我们只是从路由函数中移动了一些代码
we just moved some code from the route functions
进入我们的控制器功能
into our controller functions
现在我们的资源或我们的熊只是名字
right now our resources or our bears are just names
但资源通常有
but resources typically have
其他属性
other attributes
我们知道
and we know
如何为具有多个属性的实体建模
how to model entities that have multiple attributes
我们定义一个具有特定字段的结构
we define a structure with specific fields
所以让我们定义一个熊结构
so let's define a bear structure
我们将它放在一个名为 Bear 的文件中
we'll put it in a file called bear
ex 查找模块
ex to find the module
调查熊
survey bear
然后在里面我们将定义我们的结构
then inside of there we'll define our structure
我们的熊将有一个 id 初始值为 nil
and our bears will have an id initial value will be nil
他们会有名字
they'll have a name
这将默认为空字符串
which will default to an empty string
他们还将有一个类型，它将是一个空字符串
they'll also have a type which will be an empty string
然后我们会在那里放一个冬眠标志
and then we'll put a hibernating flag on there
指示熊是否在冬眠
to indicate whether the bear is hibernating or not
我们将默认为 false
and we'll default that to false
那么我们只需要创建一些实例
then we just need to create some instances of
这个裸露的结构
this bare structure
所以我们应该在哪里做
so where should we do that
好吧，我们可以在索引函数中做到这一点
well we could do that in the index function
但这是另一个想法
but here's another idea
让我们创建一个新模块
let's create a new module
为获取提供了一些抽象
that provides some abstraction for fetching
我们的任何野生资源
any of our wild resources
让我们称新模块为野物
let's call the new module wild things
当然我会把它放在文件wild things dot中
sure I'll put it in the file wild things dot
这是非常疯狂的事情
it's very wild things
然后我们将使用我们的熊
and then we're going to be using our bear
击中这里
struck inside of here
所以我要化名
so I'm going to alias
调查熊
survey bear
然后我们想要运行
and then we want to function
返回一个
that returns a
示例熊列表
list of example bears
我有一个排队的
and I have one of those queued up
我就贴在这里
I'll just paste it in right here
所以它只是一个包含严格实例的列表
so it's just a list that contains bear strict instances
注意我们已经通过了
notice we've got one through
锡在这里用不同的名字
tin here with different names
不同的类型和
different types and
其中一些正在冬眠
some of them are hibernating
你可以在笔记中找到这些例子
and you can pick up these examples in the note
所以你不必输入所有这些
so you don't have to type all this in
所以我们会把它保存起来
so we'll save that away
我们想在我们的熊控制器中使用它
we want to use that over in our bear controller
所以我将首先将其别名
so I'm going to start by just aliasing that in
别名调查野物
alias survey wild things
然后我们想把熊的名单记下来
and then we want to get our list of bears down
关于索引函数
on the index function
所以我们要说熊
so we're going to say bears
野生动物清单熊
wild things list bears
然后我们要做的下一件事
and then the next thing we want to do
是转换熊的名单
is transform the list of bears
现在有熊结构
there are bear structures right now
我们想将它们转换成一个 html 列表
we want to transform them into an html list
所以我们要返回的
so what we're going to return
在响应正文中不会是逗号
in the response body isn't going to be a comma
熊名字的分隔字符串
separated string of bear names
相反，它将是一个 html ul
instead it's going to be an html ul
在里面我们会有一个 li
and inside of that we'll have an li
对于每只熊，我们将拥有
for each of the bears so we'll have
这里有一个熊的名字，它的类型
a bear name here and it's type
我们会有
and we'll have
但是我们有很多熊
however many of those we have bears
那么我们将如何转换这个 struts 列表
so how are we going to transform this list of struts
进入这个 html
into this html
好吧，新的
well the e new
模块包括一堆
module includes a bunch of
您可能会使用的功能
functions that you've likely
用于其他编程语言
used in other programming languages
用于处理列表
for working with lists
所以在我的前任让我们看看恩对我们有什么好处
so over an I ex let's see what e n has for us
我将使用他的新点我只是要点击标签
I'll use h e new dot I'm just going to hit tab
好吧，它有一堆熟悉的功能
well it has a bunch of familiar functions
所以如果我在这里向上滚动
so if I just scroll up here
你会注意到它有每个
you'll notice it has each
它有过滤器它有地图
it has filter it has map
我们有减少
we've got reduce
并拒绝
and reject
它有各种各样的功能
it has all sorts of functions
但我们想做的是
but what we want to do is
将字符串列表转换为 html 项列表
transform a list of strings to a list of html items
这是地图功能的工作
and that's a job for the map function
是的，让我们看看文档
yeah let's look at the documentation for that
也是有能力的地图
it's map with an ability too
所以它所做的是转换这个给定的列表
so what it does is that transforms this given list
进入新列表
into a new list
通过应用这个
by applying this
第二个功能
function which is the second
映射函数的参数
parameter to the map function
第二个参数是一个匿名函数
and this 2nd parameter is an anonymous function
匿名函数用这个 fn 分隔
anonymous functions are delimited with this fn
然后一个
and then a
在这种情况下，参数列表只有一个称为 x
list of parameters in this case just one called x
然后它有这个箭头
then it has this arrow
然后这是函数的主体
and then this is the body of the function
它只需要 x 并将其乘以 2
it just takes x and multiplies it by two
然后就结束了
and then there's an end
所以它应用了这个功能
so it applies this function
给定列表中的每个元素
to each element in the given list
把双数还给我们
giving us back the double numbers
所以让我们把它从这里复制出来
so let's just copy this out of here
我们将它粘贴到
and we'll paste it in
我要将函数体更改为
I'm going to change the function body to
实际上是数字的三倍
actually triple the numbers
我们得到一个三元数的列表
and we get back a list of the triple numbers
现在匿名函数
now anonymous functions
是长生不老药中的一流价值
are first class values in elixir
所以我们可以将它们绑定到变量
so we can bind them to variables
假设我们想将它绑定到变量三元组
let's say we wanted to bind it to variable triple
我可以把这个拿在这里
I can just take this here
并像这样粘贴
and paste it like that
现在我们有一个名为 Triple 的函数
and now we have a function called triple
并调用该函数
and to call the function
我们说三重
we say triple
然后给一个点
and then give a dot
和括号，然后传入参数
and parentheses and then pass in the argument
在这种情况下 10
in this case 10
我们回到三倍值 30
and we get back to triple value 30
现在重要的是要注意这个点
now it's important to note that this dot
在可变三元组和假肢之间
between the variable triple and the prostheses
需要调用匿名函数
is required to invoke an anonymous function
它将它与调用名称函数区分开来
it differentiates it from calling a name function
可能在模块内的其他地方
which could be somewhere else inside of a module
因为匿名函数是一等值，我们可以
since anonymous functions are first class values we can
也将它们作为参数传递
also pass them as arguments
到地图等其他功能
to other functions such as map
所以如果我们拿地图
so if we take map
给它一个 1 2 3 的列表
give it a list of 1 2 3
然后而不是倾斜匿名函数
then instead of inclining the anonymous function
我们可以给它三倍
we could just give it triple
我们得到同样的东西
and we get the same thing
所以我们可以像我们一样内联函数
so we can either inline the function like we did
第一次
the first time
或者我们可以将它分配给一个变量
or we can assign it to a variable
然后将该函数作为参数传递
and then pass that function as an argument
所以让我们再看几个
so let's peek at a few more
将函数作为参数的函数
en functions that take a function as an argument
确定其中一个熟悉的人都想成为他们
sure one of the familiar wants to be em each
它需要一个列表和一个函数
it takes a list and a function
然后它调用该函数
and then it calls that function
对于列表中的每个元素
for each of the elements in the list
还有鸸鹋发现
there's also emu find
它需要一个函数中的列表
it takes a list in a function
返回一个真值
that returns a truth value
或者你可能认为这是一个谓词函数
or you might consider this a predicate function
以及列表中的第一项
and the first item in the list for which
该函数返回一个真值
that function returns a truth value
好吧，它被退回了
well it's returned
还有酶过滤器
there's also enzyme filter
在这种情况下，它运行函数
in this case it runs the function
在每个元素上找出哪个
on each of the elements to figure out which
保留的，以便过滤 1 2 3
ones to keep so it filtered 1 2 3
它正在寻找所有的偶数，它返回了两个
it was looking for all the evens and it returned two
最后是鸸鹋减少
and then finally there's emu reduce
这个很有趣
and this one's kind of interesting
因为它需要一个列表
because it takes a list
然后它取一个初始值
and then it takes an initial value
然后是这里的第三个参数
and then the third argument here
是一个匿名函数
is an anonymous function
但请注意这个匿名函数有两个参数
but notice this anonymous function takes two arguments
x 和一个累加器
x and an accumulator
并且你可能在其他语言中使用过 reduce
and you've probably used reduced in other languages
它所做的是将这个列表减少到一个值
what it does is reduces this list down to a value
在这种情况下，它是 6，它是这样做的
in this case it's six and it's doing that by
添加每个元素
adding each element
每次通过这个循环到这个累加器
to this accumulator each time through this loop
所以这个例子只是对数字列表求和
so this example just sums the list of numbers